<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>R - Tag - Peter Belai - R and data blog</title>
        <link>/tags/r/</link>
        <description>R - Tag - Peter Belai - R and data blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>peter.belai@gmail.com (Peter Belai)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>peter.belai@gmail.com (Peter Belai)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/r/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Creating singleton pattern in S4</title>
    <link>/2020-06-12-creating-singleton-pattern-in-s4/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/2020-06-12-creating-singleton-pattern-in-s4/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In my previous post, we have been creating a package with a connection to the database. However, this connection was exposed as a global object, which could then be freely accessed by anyone. I didn&rsquo;t like this approach, so I have decided to try to find a way how to encapsulate it and hide this object from the user of the package.
As someone, who used to work with Java and Scala before transitioning to R, singleton immediately came into my mind.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Scraping financial statements of Slovak financial entities</title>
    <link>/2020-06-07-scraping-financial-statements-of-slovak-financial-entities/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>/2020-06-07-scraping-financial-statements-of-slovak-financial-entities/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It is always interesting to go back to your older projects. You can spot, how is your coding style evolving, and how you, as a programmer, are improving. Recently, I had to go through the code of one of my first projects in R and boy, was it a mess. It was supposed to download Financial Statements of all the businesses in Slovakia for a certain year. It worked, barely. But trying to understand the code was a pain.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
